sertifi.com 2015-07-20

# Sertifi Privacy Policy | Sertifi: Electronic Signatures & eSignatures

Sertifi.com Incorporated ("Sertifi") respects your privacy and has created this privacy statement ("Statement") in order to demonstrate our commitment to customer privacy. This policy governs web sites owned and operated by Sertifi, including [www.sertifi.com](http://www.sertifi.com/) We have established this Statement as a means to communicate our information gathering and dissemination practices to our customers and visitors. This online privacy policy describes how we use, disclose and protect personal information that you share with us. "Personal information" is information that enables us to identify you, such as your name and e-mail address. By using this Site, you agree to this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Site.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, you should first contact Sertifi Support at [support@sertifi.com](mailto:support@sertifi.com).

**Information Collection and Use**

Our purpose in collecting personal information is to provide and assist you in sending and signing agreements and general use of our web contracting platform. We require customers who register to use the services offered on our Sites (collectively, the "Service") to give us contact information, such as their name, company name, address, phone number, and e-mail address, and financial qualification and billing information, such as billing name and address, and credit card number. When you register for the Service, or when you ask for additional information from Sertifi about the Service, we may also ask you for additional personal information, such as title, department name, fax number, or additional company information, such as annual revenues, number of employees, or industry. Customers can opt out of providing this additional information by not providing it when asked to do so.

Sertifi uses the information that we collect to set up the Service for customers and their organizations. We may also use the information to contact customers to discuss customer interest in our company, the Service that we provide, and to send information regarding our company or partners, such as promotions and events. Customers can opt out of being contacted by us, or receiving such information from us, at any time by submitting their email.

All financial and billing information that we collect through the Site is used solely to check the qualifications of prospective customers and to bill for the Service. This billing information is not used by Sertifi for marketing or promotional purposes. Sertifi uses a third-party intermediary to manage the credit card processing. This intermediary is solely a link in the distribution chain, and is not permitted to store, retain, or use the information provided, except for the sole purpose of credit card processing.

Customers of the Service will be using the Site to host data and information ("Data"). Sertifi will not share, distribute, print, or reference any such Data except as provided in the Sertifi Terms of Service or as may be required by law. Individual records may at times be viewed or accessed only for the purpose of resolving a problem, support issue, or suspected violation of the Terms of Service or as may be required by law. Of course, customers are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality and security of their user registration and password.

Sertifi may also collect certain information from visitors to and customers of the Site, such as Internet IP addresses. This information is logged to help operate our web contracting service, diagnose technical problems, and to administer our Site in order to constantly improve the quality of the Site and our Service. We may also track and analyze non-identifying and aggregate usage and volume statistical information ("Aggregated Information") from our visitors and customers.

We post customer testimonials on our web site which may contain personally identifiable information such as the customer's name. We do obtain the customer's consent prior to posting the testimonial to post their name along with their testimonial.

**Information Sharing and Disclosure**

Sertifi will not sell or rent your personal information, including customer e-mail addresses, to anyone. We may disclose your personal information to our third party contractors who perform services for Sertifi Incorporated in order to complete or confirm your transaction. These contractors are permitted to use the personal information only for the purposes of such services, unless we have your permission for any other use.

Sertifi Incorporated may disclose and transfer the information obtained from you through this Site or the Service as part of a merger, acquisition or other sale of its assets or business.  
Moreover, we may be legally obligated to disclose information to the government or to third parties under certain circumstances, such as illegal activity on our Site. Sertifi reserves the right to release personal information to its service providers, law enforcement or other government officials or in response to a formal request in a civil action, as Sertifi Incorporated, in our sole and absolute discretion, deems necessary or appropriate.

We may also provide Aggregated Information to third parties. Such information will not include personal information of any customer or visitor.

**Opt-Out Policy**

If, at any time after registering for information or ordering the Service, you change your mind about receiving promotional information from us or about our sharing information with third parties for promotional purposes, send us a request specifying your new choice. Send us an email at [support_ticket@Sertifi.com](mailto:support_ticket@Sertifi.com).

Sertifi reserves the right to send customers certain communications from relating to the Service, such as service announcements and administrative messages, that are considered part of your account, without offering you the opportunity to opt-out of receiving them.

**Correcting & Updating Your Information**

If customers need to update or change registration information they may do so by editing the user record. To update User Preferences, log on to [www.sertifi.com](http://www.sertifi.com/) update your profile section. To update billing information please e-mail [support_ticket@Sertifi.com](mailto:support_ticket@Sertifi.com)

**Cookies**

When you interact with the Site, we try to make that experience simple and meaningful. When you visit our Site, our Web server sends a cookie to your computer. Cookies are files that Web browsers place on a computer's hard drive and are used to indicate whether you have visited the Site previously.

Choices about Cookies: You can configure your browser to accept all cookies, reject all cookies, or notify you when a cookie is set. (Each browser is different, so check the "Help" menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences.)

If you reject all cookies, you will not be able to use Sertifi Incorporated products or services that require you to "sign in," and you may not be able to take full advantage of all offerings.  
Our Practices Regarding Cookies: Sertifi uses session and persistent cookies for a number of purposes, including to: access your account information when you "sign in," so that we can provide you with customized content; keep track of preferences you specify while you are using Sertifi services; estimate and report our total audience size and traffic; and conduct research to improve Sertifi Incorporated content and services.

Third Party Cookies: We may from time to time engage third parties to track and analyze non-personally identifiable usage and volume statistical information from visitors to our Site to help us administer our Site and improve its quality. Such third parties may use cookies to help track visitor behavior. Such cookies will not be used to associate individual website visitors to any personally identifiable information. All data collected by such third parties on behalf of Sertifi is used only to provide us with information on Site usage and is not shared with any other third parties.

**Security and Data Storage**

Our Site has security measures in place to help protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of the personal information and Data under our control. Sertifi hosts the Site in a secure server environment that uses a firewall and other industry-standard technology to help prevent interference or access from outside intruders. Sertifi also requires that unique user names and passwords must be entered each time a customer logs on to the Site.

Sertifi keeps your account information active in our user registration databases in order to provide immediate access to your personalization preferences and data each time you visit the Site. If you ask Sertifi to delete your Sertifi account, in most cases your account will be deactivated and then deleted from our user registration database in approximately 90 days. This delay is necessary to discourage users from engaging in fraudulent activity. Please note that any information that we have copied may remain in back-up storage for some period of time after your deletion request. This may be the case even though no information about your account remains in our active user databases.

**Sertifi, Inc. Safe Harbor Privacy Notice**

Sertifi, Inc. ("Sertifi") is committed to the privacy principles agreed upon separately by the European Union and Switzerland with the United States with respect to Personal Information (as defined below). We value our relationship with our clients and certify that we comply with the US-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the US-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework, including the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles regarding Personal Information transferred from European Economic Area ("EEA"), European Union ("EU") and Switzerland to the United States ("US"). Sertifi's practices fostering compliance with Safe Harbor Privacy Principles is set forth below, in this Notice ("Notice").

"Personal Information" for the purposes of this policy shall mean information that (i) is transferred from EEA, EU and Switzerland to the US, (ii) is recorded in any form, (iii) that is information collected such as name, email address, postal address and telephone number, and (iv) could be linked to an individual. This Personal Information is for the intended use of our clients only.

**Safe Harbor Privacy Principles**

Sertifi's practices regarding the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles, as set forth by the US Department of Commerce in consultation with the the European Commission and the Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner of Switzerland, satisfy the requirement under EU and Swiss law that adequate protection be given to Personal Information transferred from the EEA and the EU or Switzerland to the US.

**Notice**

Where Sertifi collects personal information directly from its EU and Swiss customers, it informs them about the purpose for which it collects and uses their personal information, the choices they have to limit the use of personal information about them, and how to contact Sertifi. Beyond that, We have no direct relationship with our customers' customers whose personal data we processes.

**Choice**

Sertifi shall provide its customers with a choice to opt out of disclosure of their personal information to a third party or the use of the personal information for something other than it was originally collected.

**Onward Transfer**

Before disclosing personal information to a third party, Sertifi shall notify the customer of the intended disclosure and shall provide the customer with the option to opt out of such disclosure.

**Access**

Upon request, Sertifi Inc. will grant individuals reasonable access to personal information that it holds about them. In addition, Sertifi Inc. will take reasonable steps to permit individuals to correct, amend, or delete information that is demonstrated to be inaccurate or incomplete. We will respond to your request for access within 30 days.

**Security**

Sertifi takes reasonable precautions to protect Personal Information from loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, and destruction.

**Data Integrity**

Sertifi Incorporated takes reasonable steps to ensure that your personal information we process is accurate, complete, and current by using the most recent information provided to us.

**Enforcement**

Sertifi will investigate and attempt to resolve complaints and disputes regarding processing and disclosure of Personal Information in accordance with the principles contained in this Notice. For complaints resolved internally, Sertifi's remedy will be reasonable, and sufficient corrective action to resolve the complaint, including correcting any Personal Information, using Personal Information consistent with the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles, reversing or correcting the effects of noncompliance, and assuring that future processing of Personal Information will be in conformity with the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles. Complaints that cannot be resolved between Sertifi will be handled by EU Data Protection Authorities (EU DPAs).

Please address any questions or concerns regarding our Safe Harbor Privacy Notice or our practices regarding Personal Information to:

**Sertifi Support Group**  
1.866.983.8877

Sertifi, Inc.  
350 N. LaSalle Suite 1020  
Chicago, IL 60654
